准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
怪物岛的外卖
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
我很清楚自己今天要吃什么
I know exactly what I'm gonna eat today
等等  话说我干啥要进来
Wait, why did I come in here, again?
我猜猜看
Lemme guess--
不要提醒我
Don't tell me
是蟹字开头的
Starts with a K
把肉饼放烤架上
Throwin' patties on the grill
拿着配料玩杂耍
Juggling ingredients
千万不要撒一地
Trying not to spill
烤架点上火
The grill aflame
工作似玩乐
Work is a game
大功告成  就能拥有面包
When I'm done, you'll have a bun
充满无限美味
Full of yum, yum, yum
好
Yes
我的计划完美实现中
My plan is working perfectly
三度烫伤不算
Minus the third degree burns
现在巧妙撤出蟹堡王
And now, for my clever escape
你这是想去哪
Where do you think you're going?
想趁外卖还没送出去偷偷溜走是吧
Trying to sneak out before the big delivery, huh?
没必要临阵脱逃  小小蟹黄堡
No need to get cold feet, little patty
你在新家一定会幸福快乐不少的
You'll be very happy in your new home
不好了
Oh, no
我送外卖要迟到了
I'm gonna be late for my delivery
八十分钟后
蟹堡王
你放心  小小蟹黄堡
Don't worry, little patty
你就快到家了
you're almost home
等等
Wait
裤头村
泥巴海
百慕大三角
有软软的东西给我做缓冲了
Something soft broke my fall
谢了  蟹黄堡
Thanks, patty
蟹黄堡
Patty
我们好像已经出裤头村了
I don't think we're in Bikini Bottom anymore
我们肯定是在泥巴海迷路了
We must be lost in the deep Goo Sea
看来外卖送不到了
I guess we'll miss the delivery
我让可怜的蟹老板失望了
I've let down poor, old Mr. Krabs
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我只是要去
I'm just going to the, uh
上个小号
little patty's room?
怎么不早说
Why didn't you say so?
我会小心转过身去
I'll discreetly turn around
给你点隐私的
and give you a little privacy
等一下
Wait a minute
我没做过小号蟹黄堡
I don't make little patties
你想得美  痞老板
Nice try, Plankton
快回来
Get back here
等一下  我们被困了
Wait a minute, we're marooned
必须把蟹黄堡留到最后一刻
We have to make this patty last
这可是我们获救前的唯一食物
It's our only food until we're rescued
所以呢
So?
你想表达什么
What's your point?
要是想活下来  就必须分享
If we're gonna survive, we'll have to share
分享
Share?
一言为定  大兄弟
You've got yourself a deal, big boy
来握个手
Put 'er there, pal
来  你可以吃第一口
Here, you can have the first bite
吃得少一点
Make it a small one
不介意我就开吃了
Don't mind if I do
真奇怪
That's strange
痞老板
Plankton?
这蟹黄堡味道有点
This patty tastes a little
生气
angry
痞老板
Plankton
你没事
You're okay
还以为要失去你了
I thought I lost you
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
够了
Enough
对不起
Sorry
必须趁还没天黑赶紧开始找避难所
We have to start looking for shelter
before it gets dark
那蛇怪先生呢
What about Mr. Snake Monster?
能跟我们一块避难吗
Can he come stay with us?
不行
No
抱歉
Sorry
我尽力了
I tried
不算太破
Not too shabby
不错
Yep
痞老板  能把腿挪过去一点点吗
Plankton, could you move your leg over a little?
里面有点挤
It's a bit cramped in here
幸好有刺可以做缓冲
Lucky these thorns broke our fall
是啊  我真是幸好
Yeah, lucky me
这地方看着挺宽敞
This place looks pretty spacious
完全可以在这整不少东西
We can really do a lot with this place
那边可以当你房间
Over there can be your room
这边可以当我房间
That could be my room
里头是不是有点黑啊
It's a little dark back here, isn't it?
可以听到我回声
I can hear my echo
你有没有觉得里面有点湿啊
Does it feel a little wet in here to you?
快看
Look
我找到电灯开关了
I found a light switch
嗨  痞老板
Hey, Plankton
新计划
New plan
来吃点东西吧
Let's grab a bite to eat
快看
Look
有香蕉
Bananas
总算有东西吃了
Finally, some grub
来吃吧
Let's eat
妈妈
Mama
要吃这块石头吗
Should we eat this rock?
我什么都能吃
I'll eat anything
快走开
Leave us alone
开
椰子小屋
盛大开业
今天的活儿干得不错
Great work out there today
没有你的生活完全不一样
It's just not the same without you
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了  痞老板
Yes, Plankton?
你想的跟我一样吗
Are you thinkin' what I'm thinkin'?
对  我也拿不定主意
Yep, I can't decide either
员工运动衫
Do the company sports jerseys
要米黄色还是绿色才好看
look better in beige or green?
错了  你个白痴
No, you imbecile
我们现在得逃跑
It's time for us to am-scray
怪不知物不觉地回去
and get back home without the monsters noticing
怪物到处都在盯着我们  痞老板
They're watching us everywhere, Plankton
快逃
Run for it
鼻潜
Nose dive
太多怪物了
Too many monsters
椰子小屋
海绵宝宝  我有办法了
SpongeBob, I have an idea
照着我做
Follow my lead
好了怪物们
All right, monsters
我们这就回去干活
We'll go back to work
马上去做好吃的椰子堡
and whip up some nice coconut patties
其实
In fact
我们为大家准备了盛大又美味的惊喜
we have a big, delicious surprise for you
只要你们闭上眼睛
You just have to close your eyes
好
Good
把耳朵捂住  然后唱
Now stick your fingers in your ears and sing
趁现在快跑
Now, run
正在供应
椰子堡
再见了
Goodbye
威胁吃掉我们  俘虏我们的朋友们
friends who kept us captive by threatening to eat us
你办法想得可真好  痞老板
Great thinking back there, Plankton
要不要来庆祝一下胜利呢
How about we celebrate our victory?
干杯
Cheers
等一下
Wait
我们怎么朝岛那边往回走了
Why are we heading back to the island?
我觉得是岛在朝我们这边走
I think the island is heading back to us
欢迎来到酷乐湖
借过一下
Comin' through
刚才真是好险
That was a close one
蟹堡王
你迟到了  海绵宝宝
You're late, SpongeBob
你前六年都哪去了
Where have you been the last six years?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
美好时光就这么结束了
Well, it was nice while it lasted
无海绵宝宝
天数
地震来了
It's an earthquake
大家快逃
Run for your lives
不要
No
别吃蟹堡王
Not me restaurant
正在供应
椰子堡
我知道我今天想吃什么了
I know what I want to eat today
我要来份椰子堡
I'll have one coco patty
马上就来
Comin' right up
不过要收点小小的服务费
for a nominal service charge
现在皆大欢喜了
All's well that ends well
对吧  痞老板
eh, Plankton?
不好了
Oh, no
痞老板哪去了
Where's Plankton?
我们总算一块儿独处了
We're alone at last
派大星
快点骑
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
早安  派大星
Good morning, Patrick
早安  海绵宝宝
Good morning, SpongeBob
要来骑自行车穿越水母田吗
Wanna go for a bike ride through jellyfish fields?
那是当然要的了
You bet your square pants I do
我好爱骑车
I love bike riding
我都忘了我没自行车
I forgot I don't have a bike
没关系
No problem
我有辆备用的
I have a spare
你先等一下  我找车得找好一会儿
Hold on, it'll just take me a minute to find it
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
我好像找不
I just can't seem to
到
Find it
看看这辆上品好车啊
Check out this sweet ride
谢了  小蜗
Thanks, Gare Bear
走吧  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
快跟我来
Follow me
对了
Oh, yeah
我不会骑自行车
I don't know how to ride a bike
我没法跟你一起骑车了  海绵宝宝
I guess I can't go bike riding with you, SpongeBob
你的漂亮粉红尖头可不要担心
Now, don't you worry your pretty, pink, pointy head
我可以教你当个专业自行车骑手
I can teach you how to be an expert bicyclist
好啊
Nice
我要当个滋冰辙起手了
I'm gonna be an icicle mist
第一课
Lesson one
如何正确坐上自行车
How to properly sit on a bike
面向前方
Face forward
保持双臂平行  但要松弛
arms parallel but loose
两脚紧紧站在沙地上
both feet placed firmly on the sand
那好
Okay then
我开始了
Here I go
转身
Turn around
另一边
Other side
差一点
But not quite
好
Okay, uh
就快成了
gettin' here
这样行不行
How's this?
还是手把手来教比较好
Maybe we need a more hands-on approach
紧紧抓牢车把
Handlebars grasped firmly
让屁股坐好  脚踩稳
Tushy planted, feet stable
然后  哒哒
and ta-da
成功了
I did it
不用担心  只要掌握要领就行了
Don't worry, you just need to get the hang of it
对  就快掌握了
Yeah, almost got it
快成了
Nearly there
差一点了
Close
知道不  派大星
You know, Patrick
感觉是你对重力应付不来
I think you have gravity trouble
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about
气球应该能让你直直稳定好
Those should keep you upright
还是装辅助轮好了
Maybe some training wheels
这样就能让你稳定点了
That'll make you a little more stable
我精神病医生就说这种话
That's what my psychiatrist says
得检查下你脑袋了
Time to check under the hood
正如我所料
Just as I thought
你大脑有点不太平衡
Your brain's a bit unbalanced
现在来试试看
Now give it a try
有人应该准备好要开骑了
I think someone's ready to pedal
我也这么觉得
I think so, too
谁啊
Who?
就这样
That's it
现在轻轻踩踏板
Now, pedal nice and easy
千万别放手
And don't you let go
你放心  兄弟
Don't worry, buddy
我绝对不会把手从车上放下来
I won't take my hands off this bike
我保证
I promise
我做到了
I'm doing it
我没放手
I didn't let go
你要有东西来帮你集中注意聚焦前方
You need something to help you focus
早就想到了
Way ahead of ya
你好啊
Hello
好啊
Yeah
起效了  派大星
It's working, Patrick
你表现特别棒
You're doing great
现在认真看我做
For now, just observe me
仔细看看车要怎么骑
Take a closer look and see how it's done
看我脚  学我做
Watch my feet, and do what I do
对了
That's it
你要掌握诀窍了
Now you're getting it
现在踏板踩快一点点
Now pedal just a little faster
快一点点
Faster?
有点太快了  派大星
A little too fast there, Patrick
放松一下
Just relax
我可放松了
I'm relaxed
好高兴
I'm so happy
我们能有专属的两人时光  阿芙
we have some time to ourselves, Puffykins
不会突然冒出来个
Without any interruptions from--
小心
Look out
海绵
Sponge
宝宝
Bob
你们两个海底白痴到底在
What in the name of all that's salty
are you two dipsy doodles--
章鱼哥
Squidward
什么
What?
章鱼哥
Squidward
果然如此
Of course
嗨  泡芙老师
Hi, Mrs. Puff
你好  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
跟你说吧  我有点不太会
You know, I'm having a little trouble
教好派大星学骑自行车
trying to teach Patrick how to ride a bicycle
你也有教不好的同学吗  泡芙老师
Have you ever had trouble teaching a student, Mrs. Puff?
有些人就是教了就忘
Some people are just unteachable
墙
教了就忘
Unteachable?
忘掉
Unteach
有了
That's it
谢了  泡芙老师
Thanks, Mrs. Puff
下次就在家约会好了
We're having out next date at home
知道你问题出在哪吗  派大星
You know what your problem is, Patrick?
你的大脑充斥着各种不重要的知识
Your brain is just too full of unimportant knowledge
是啊  塞得满满当当
Yeah, it is pretty jam-packed
还是说塞得全都是果酱
Or is it packed with jam?
得给你脑袋腾空  方便学骑车
We need to make some room in your head for bike riding
我想想
Let's see
你还记得要怎么刷牙吗
Do you remember how to brush your teeth?
那当然了
Of course
我连怎么梳牙都知道
I even know how to comb my teeth
现在你俩都不知道了
Well, now you don't
要怎么看电视
How to watch TV?
这种事不重要
Nah, not important
穿裤子
Put on your pants?
高估自己了
Overrated
家人
Family?
没多大必要
Unnecessary
消除很多记忆后
派大星  你叫什么名字
Patrick, what is your name?
我谁是
Who is I?
有人终于准备好
I think someone's finally ready
要开始骑车了
to ride a bicycle
好了  派大星
All right, Patrick
你准备好了
You're ready
还有一件事得记住
There's just one more thing to remember--
要开开心心
have fun
开心
我对骑车一窍不通
I have no knowledge of bike riding
派大星  现在下车还来得及
Patrick, get off that bike before it's too late
你放心  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
死人山
放弃一切希望
这里可是面包人山
It's just Bread Man's Hill
这不是面包人山
That's not Bread Man's Hill
是死人山
it's Dead Man's Hill
什么
Wha--
有那么严重吗
is that worse?
好像还挺严重
It sounds worse
真的很严重
It is worse
不
No
海绵宝宝  我做到了
SpongeBob, I'm doing it
我在骑车了
I'm bicycling
活人平地
第一航海银行
市政厅
为纪念你成为有史以来最伟大的骑手
In honor of becoming
the greatest bicyclist who has ever lived
我要为你献上裤头村钥匙
I present you the key to Bikini Bottom
市长
还有锁
And the lock
派大星
Patrick
Patrick?
感谢海神王你没事
Thank Neptune you're okay
我当然没事了
Of course I'm okay
我现在是专业骑手了
I'm an expert bicyclist now
派大星  你一路摔下了死人山
Patrick, you crashed all the way down Dead Man's Hill
你都昏迷六个星期了
You've been in a coma for six weeks
破我个人记录了
A new personal best
抱歉教不会你骑自行车  派大星
Sorry I couldn't teach you how to ride a bike, Patrick
破自行车谁还用得上
Who needs a dumb bike?
我就是自行车
I am a bike
兄弟上车吧
Hop on, buddy
出发了
Let's roll
小心
Look out
急诊
我不会骑派大星
I don't know how to ride a Patrick